michelinman.com 2014-11-30

# Michelin Privacy | Michelin Tires

### Michelin Practices Related to the Protection of Confidential Personal Data

Michelin North America, Inc. ("Michelin"), respects the private lives of the visitors and users of its Internet sites.

This document describes the practices adopted by Michelin concerning personal data, including the circumstances in which it may be collected, the purposes for which it may be used, and the people for which it is intended.

Each Michelin Internet site has a particular aim and has characteristics which are unique to it. If additional personal data acquisitions are necessary for a Michelin Internet site in particular, you will be so informed on the site.

#### Table of Contents

  * Personal Data
  * Collection of Personal Data
  * Use of Personal Data
  * Recipients of your personal data
  * Shelf Life
  * Right of access, Modification, or Opposition
  * Data Security
  * Cookies
  * International Transfers of Personal Data
  * Interactive Services
  * Minors
  * Links to Third Party Sites
  * Trademark and Copyright Notice
  * Consent to This Privacy Policy
  * Sweepstakes Rules
  * Amendments

#### Personal Data

Generally, most Michelin Internet sites do not require you to disclose your personal data.  It may be that Michelin requires you to provide your personal data in order to better meet your needs, for example, to establish a correspondence, to respond to a request, and other similar circumstances. “Personal data” may include your name, addresses, telephone number, email addresses, and other specific information such as a user name, password, or account information.

Top

#### Collection of Personal Data

Michelin will collect your personal data with precise, explicit, and legitimate goals. It will not treat this data in a way that is incompatible with these goals.  
Michelin is committed to collecting only the information that is adequate, relevant, and non-excessive, taking into consideration the goal for which it is collected. Michelin will take all reasonable measures to ensure that the personal data collected is accurate. 

Top

#### Use of Personal Data

Michelin uses your personal data within the strict limits of the goals for which it was collected.  As an example, Michelin may use your personal data to:

  * Provide you with information on its products and services;
  * Carry out and follow your transactions;
  * Allow you to take part in the interactive aspects of its sites; and
  * Communicate, develop, and trade with you.

Michelin is committed to not using your personal data without your prior consent.

Top

#### Recipients of your personal data

The recipients of your personal data are limited exclusively to the people who have a business need to know.  
Michelin may share your personal data with third party suppliers or service providers. These suppliers and service providers are contractually obligated to keep your personal data confidential and secure, and they are required to use your personal data only for the needs for the services that were entrusted to them.  
Michelin will not sell or rent your personal data to third parties without your consent, except pursuant to a court order, to comply with applicable law, or to protect the rights and the goods of Michelin.

Top

#### Shelf Life

Michelin will not preserve your personal data any longer than it is necessary to achieve the goals for which it was collected or for the time period required by law.

Top

#### Right of access, Modification, or Opposition

You can ask Michelin for access to your personal data in its possession, and you may modify this data if it is not accurate. You have the right to prohibit Michelin from collecting or disclosing your personal data. As regards commercial prospection, you can use your right of opposition without any justification. For the exercise of these rights, please notify the webmaster of the Internet site concerned and/or the Privacy Officer.   

Top

#### Data Security

Michelin has established measures to ensure the confidentiality, safety and integrity of its systems containing your personal data. The access to the personal data is restricted to those with a business need to know and who are required to observe these rules.  
On Michelin’s commercial sites, the collection of the banking coordinates will be carried out within the framework of effective processes of security of the payments. These measurements can consist of encryption during the collection or transfer of confidential data. Michelin takes care to ensure that your personal data is not altered, damaged or misused.

Top

#### Cookies

Michelin collects data relating to how you use our Internet sites to improve our service to visitors and users of these sites through the use of cookies, which are files that your Internet navigator places on your hard disk when you visit a site. The cookies do not make it possible to identify you personally. The recorded data can be information such as which pages you consulted, the date and time of such consultation, and other tracking information.  
You can parameterize your navigator so that it informs you of the presence of cookies and provides you with the option of accepting the cookies. You can also parameterize your navigator to decontaminate the cookies.

Top

#### International Transfers of Personal Data

Michelin is an international company that has databases in the various countries where it operates. Michelin can transfer your personal data within the company or to its external partners located outside of your home country.  
Because the level of data protection is not homogeneous on a world level, we do not transmit your personal data to third party companies outside of the European Union unless these companies offer contractually the same or similar level of protection of your personal data that Michelin offers.   
For the transfers within Michelin, the company has adopted Binding Corporate Rules (“BCRs”) to govern the transfers of personal data coming from the European Union. If you click on “BCRs,” you will find a copy of the rules.

Top

#### Interactive Services

Certain Michelin Internet sites contain interactive functions. You can, if you wish it, use these interactive functions by filling a form with inscription. This form requires you to disclose certain personal data. This personal data is collected with an aim of improving the interactive services and of meeting your needs. The users registered with these services can have access to the information provided at the time of the inscription, and they have the right to modify or destroy the information provided at any time.

Top

#### Minors

Michelin Internet sites are generally not intended for minors (less than eighteen (18) years of age). If you are a minor, we encourage you not to transmit personal information without the authorization of your parents.

Top

#### Links to Third Party Sites

Michelin Internet sites can include hyperlinks to third party sites. Michelin does not control these sites and thus cannot be held responsible for their practices relating to the confidentiality and security of your personal data. We invite you to review those sites’ privacy policies before using them or providing them with your personal data.

Top

#### Trademark and Copyright Notice

Please consult our Terms of Use for further information.

Top

#### Consent to This Privacy Policy

By using this website, you signify your assent to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with any term in this Policy, please do not use this site or submit any personally identifiable information.

Top

Top

#### Amendments

This Policy became effective on April 15, 2011. Any amendments will be posted at this URL and will be effective when posted. Thus, please check this page periodically.

Top
